analyst invited me to speak a little bit
about the rising regeneration movement
around the world or what I call the
regeneration rising I think that all of
us alive today are challenged in our
lifetimes to redesign the human impact
on earth to fundamentally change our
ways to become healers of a wounded
planet that we wounded and to do what we
can to turn this runaway climate change
around it turns into cataclysmic climate
change and the good news is that this is
happening all over the world and one of
the core principles of regenerative
development is it starts with personal
development so I'm gonna echo a lot of
what has already been said rex mentioned
a lot of wonderful things that stay
active like we by the power of our
attention and the power of our intention
we shape this world there's nothing that
we cannot like that we do or don't do
that doesn't affect the whole that we're
a part of so just a loving attention
towards trying to be part of the healing
rather than part of the destruction of
Mother Earth is already making a
difference and so it is an internal it
is a spiritual path it is a personal
development path but it's also a very
practical path out there and for example
Paul Hawkens object drawdown has listed
a hundred ways that we can draw carbon
out of the atmosphere already right now
and there is a global movement on
regenerative agriculture that is
changing how we grow our food in ways
that farmers become guardians of
ecosystems health and there's a global
more academic and policy driven movement
around planetary health I've wrote my
PhD in 2006 on designed for human and
Planetary health and was really
surprised when because initially nobody
wanted to know about it and in 2017 the
Rockefeller Foundation and The Lancet
the key Medical Journal
published a report on planetary health
and for all of you out there this could
be just like the SDGs with all their
flaws are an invitation and a platform
for a conversation we need to have right
now also about their flaws in a similar
way this planetary health concept which
is already a hundred and twenty
universities and government policy think
tanks lined up around the planet is a
key entry point for us to work on all of
this I see a confluence on the planet as
we see the converging tri-c's of Fricke
of capella mentor said if you follow the
ecological the economic and the social
crisis upstream you meet the crisis of
consciousness a crisis of perception in
a similar way if you as as the crises
are converging the solutions and those
trying to heal the planet are converging
and confluence in like like rivers
meeting and for me these are the river
planetary health everything regeneration
we've mentioned the fundamental need to
redesign our economic system is it is a
degenerative dysfunctional system and
there are people working on that the
capital institute has published a paper
on what would regenerative capitalism or
regenerative economy look like just a
couple of days ago they've published a
paper of how what would regenerative
finance look like and then there are
people like the region network and
working on new technologies that that
provide the proof of regeneration of
ecosystems so people can invest in
regeneration of ecosystems there's a lot
wonderful work going on in education the
earth wise center higher education guy
university the permaculture movement the
holistic land management movement so
many people coming together and there's
deep wisdom in the the regenerative
development process developed by our
genesis group and and i'm really excited
to see all these things coming together
and for those who are interested i gave
a talk on this at finn home post the
link and so you just get all the links
and yeah so somebody said earlier when I
loved how
brother Phil described how after all
these years of science we finally
figured out that it's all connected and
it's all interrelated and it's all
intelligent and this is the strapline of
pioneers who've done good work and
trying to bridge this gap between
indigenous knowledge and modern science
and innovative exploration of ecological
designers and engineers for decades now
and so our movement is not a new
movement our movement is a movement that
is as old as the climate change problem
and actually an ancient movement if we
finally reconnect with the wisdom that
indigenous cultures have to share to us
and as we stand up and do something
about this we do so with the power and
authority of 3.8 billion years of life's
evolution it is life speaking through us
saying enough we have done enough damage
we now need to make a difference and we
know in this is it it is local but it is
glocal it is both local and global
because we need to do the action in our
place in our bio bio region but we also
need to keep connected to learn from
each other and to keep this awareness
that everything we do everywhere is
contributing to the healing of the
planet and as we come together in all
our diversity with all our strife and
current fundamentalism of beliefs we
will heal ourselves as we heal our
ecosystem in our planet we are wounded
people
a wounded civilization were not even a
civilization worthy that name there's
too many things to go on in the name of
humanity that are uncivilized for us to
call ourselves civilization let's become
a civilization and let's do so by
healing the planet and healing ourselves
thank you